《越狱》前情回顾
Previously on Prison Break
女士们  打搅一下  我有几个问题想问你
Excuse me,ladies,I need to ask you a few questions.
再是那个邋遢的南方人
And then that dirty Southerner,
他鬼鬼祟祟地从后门走的
he snuck out the back.
你真的认为那个恋童癖卷走了所有的钱?
Do you really think the diaper sniper got all of it?
如果换作你是帝博格
If you were Bagwell,
手上有500万现钞
and you just got your hands on $5 million,
你会去哪?
where would you go?
好的 听着
All right,listen,
在彩虹轩
in the Rainbow Room.
那是纽约的一家餐厅
Restaurant in New York City.
我会在那里等着你
I am gonna be waiting in that spot.
你和女儿能在那里等着我
And that's all that I want... in this whole world,
就是我所期盼的全部了
is for my two girls to be waiting there for me.
凯莉 福斯特
Kelly Foster
三个点 第三个字母
(rendezvous:碰头地点)
问题是地点会在哪
Question is "where"?
日落
Sundown
迈克儿  什么意思? 你到底想要告诉我什么?
What? What are you trying to tell me,Michael?
我想我欠你一个道歉
I think I owe you an apology.
因为我对你撒了个谎
Because I lied to you.
关于奥斯卡  沙尔斯的事
About Oscar Shales.
就在那儿
Right there.
我就是在这枪毙了他
That's where I put the bullet in him.
你要做什么?
What are you doing,man?
你只是受雇办事的
You've been hired to do a job.
理由不关你的事
The reasoning... does not concern you.
不要问关于我们的事
You don't ask any questions about us,
这样或许我们能继续保证不再有人调查你
maybe we'll continue to make sure no one asks any questions about you.
明白了吗?
Are we clear?
全部都得死
They all die.
布兰丁植物园
blanding botanical gardens
晚班经理: 吉米  马丹
night manager:jimmy madan
嘿
Hey.
你是新来的吗?
Are you new?
没错
Yeah.
没人告诉过我会有新志愿者加入
No one told me we were getting a new volunteer.
我一直在这工作的
I've been working,uh,
上晚班做清洁工还有...
night shifts,cleanup and...
吉米说我可以换日班  所以...
Jimmy said I could change my shift,so...
你知道你要干什么吗?
You know what you're doin'?
知道
Yeah.
我四处看一圈
I'll see you around.
好的
Right.
阿帕奇沙漠之魅
apache desert ghost
-可能是斯科菲尔德 -收到
This might be Scofield.-copy that
你去那边
You take that side.
不许动!
Freeze!
别开枪
Take it easy,man.
-呆在地上别动 -发生什么事?
What's the deal?
他跑了
He's gone.
你还好吧?
How you feelin'?
算是吧
Okay,I guess.
有点疲惫
Tired.
孩子 我是他们的目标
I'm a target,kid.
只要你和我在一起 你也是他们的目标
As long as you're with me,so are you.
事情在转好之前会变得更糟
Things could get a lot worse before they get better.
你明白吗?
You understand?
但是我们碰上迈克儿叔叔 然后取道巴拿马...
But after we meet up with Uncle Mike and get to Panama...
取道巴拿马不是万全之策 你叔叔的计划有风险
Panama ain't a sure thing,your uncle's plan is dangerous.
我是说真的很危险
I mean really dangerous.
听着
Listen...
所有针对你的指控都被推翻了
all the charges against you have been dropped;
你现在是清白之身 可以开始一段新生活
you're free and clear  to start a new life.
一段美好的生活
A good life.
而非终日四处奔波提心吊胆...
Not be constantly running,looking over your shoulder...
你想要我离开?
You want me to leave?
不是
No.
当然不是
很好 我也不会离开的
Good,'cause I'm not.
詹妮  电视机开响点
Turn the sound up on the tube,Jenny.
贝丝  威尔逊芝加哥公报报道
Beth Wilson,Chicago Gazette.
你对的大卫  阿克斯死有何看法?
Do you have any thoughts on the death of David Apolskis?
非常不幸
It was unfortunate.
-验尸表明他是被近距离射杀的 -哦 可怜的大卫
Tests show he was shot at close range. Oh,David.
我想提醒你的是
Was there any opportunity to subdue him
难道就不能制服他吗
... Let me remind you that
尽管大卫  阿克斯的年纪不大
despite his age,David "Tweener" Apolskis
但他是个逃犯并扑过来抢我的枪
was a fugitive who made a move for my weapon.
我并不想朝他开枪
I did not want to have to kill him,
但是有时候你会无法控制事态
but sometimes things happen that are just out of your control.
那个勇敢的男孩难不成把你们都干了?
That good ole boy's huntin' 'em all down,ain't he?
马宏先生 有人暴料说你已恢复了斯科菲尔德的硬盘
Mr. Mahone,sources claim that you've recovered Scofield's hard drive
并从中获得大量信息
and have obtained substantial data from it.
哪来的消息?
What sources?
据其所述 你已获取有关斯科菲尔德如何越狱
Allegedly you've retrieved information detailing not only how Scofield broke out,
及出狱后的计划等详尽信息
but how he plans to stay out.
-介意评价一下此事吗? -无可奉告
Care to comment? No.
今天早些时候布兰丁植物园事件
The event at Blanding Botanical Gardens earlier today,
就是你从硬盘中取得信息的收获吧
that was a result of hard-drive data you collected.
无可奉告
No comment.
你已经找到斯科菲尔德会去的其他地方
You found other locations where Scofield might be headed?
-这是真的吗? -还是那句话"无可奉告"
True? I believe I said no comment.
这个家伙似乎已经知道
There's something about this guy,
我们会去哪  我们怎么计划的
it's like he knows where we're going,what we're thinking.
马宏先生 能否透露一下你下一步怎么走?
Mr. Mahone,could you tell us where you're headed next?
硬盘在调查过程中会起什么作用?
What role will the hard drive play in your search?
调查工作的具体进展
The details of this investigation
是极度保密并且日后也是如此
are extremely confidential and will remain so.
实验室归来 有什么发现吗?
Heard it came back from the lab,any findings?
3200安瓿的硝化甘油(炸药)
Yeah,3,200 nitroglycerine ampules.
斯科菲尔德知道这些东西需存放在阴冷潮湿之处
Scofield knew these needed to be stored in a cool,moist area.
犹他州沙漠里最好的存放点就是植物园
Best place for that in the Utah desert is the Botanical Gardens.
这东西稳定吗?
It's stable?
按照心脏病人医用单位的话很安全
All medical grade,safely used by heart patients all the time.
但是聚合在一起...
But in the aggregate...
那个盒子足够
It could take out an entire building.
炸毁整幢大楼
That box right there.
这就是我们不能从这间办公室
This is why we can't have...
泄漏丁点信息的原因
leaks...coming from this office.
上帝保佑那个
God help the agent
在我背后泄密给媒体的探员
who goes behind my back and talks to the press.
能否详细阐述下这次追捕行动的策略?
Can you elaborate on any of your tactics in this manhunt?
孙子云
Sun Tzu said,that if you know your enemy,
知己知彼百战不殆
you need not fear a hundred battles.
我了解那些逃犯
I know these men--
他们是谁 他们来自哪 他们想去哪
who they are,where they came from,where they want to go.
犹他州 莫阿布镇
Moab,Utah
那段名言是亘古有效的
these xxx are in a constant battle.
不仅仅对我 也对逃犯
not only with me, but with themselves.
预测他们做出的每个决定
second guessing of every decision they make,
往左转 还是往右转
do i turn left,do i turn right.
停下还是离开
stay or go.
我的工作就是来解开这些谜团
my job is to know how they'll answer these questions
(前妻: 帕姆  马宏  住址: 西大街90号)
打赢这场追捕战的唯一途径
The only way to win a war
就是彻底了解你的抓捕对象
is to try to know your prey completely
然后用你所掌握得一切信息
and then you get to go after your enemy
再去追捕敌人
with everything you've got.
我们半价商品在后面
Our half-priced stuff is in the back.
我在找一些非常特别的东西
I'm looking for something very specific.
那好吧
Okay.
就是这个
This is it.
这正是我想要的
This is exactly what I need.
很好
Great.
我们今天差之毫厘
We were just inches away today,inches.
我想把这些放大
I want these blown up,huge.
挂在我办公室的墙上
Put them in my office on the walls.
这些是什么?
What are these?
里面有斯科菲尔德约定的碰头地点信息
Somewhere in there is information regarding a rendezvous that Scofield set up,
我们现在就把那地点破译出来
and we're going to crack that code today.
兰! 今天是富兰克林和他妻子相约
Lang! Today's the day Franklin told his wife
-在彩虹轩见面的日子 -没错
he's going to meet her at the Rainbow Room. That's right.
错了 今天是富兰克林归案之日
Wrong. Today's the day Franklin's going down.
你准备好了吗?
Are you ready?
一切都安排妥当了
Everything's arranged.
芝加哥 伊利诺斯州
Chicago,Illinois
都在这了?
It's all here?
嘿 老兄?
Hey,yo,D. Wassup,baby?
我知道肯定就是你
I know that ain't you.
像鬼魅般浮现
Ain't a ghost,man.
你还好吧?
You holding up all right?
转乘了n辆车
Yeah. Just catching a whole bunch of buses
终于到这了
just to get here to Chi-town,man.
你觉得我会感觉如何?
How you think I'm supposed to feel?
你好  克里斯 杰伊
Chris. Jay.
富兰姆 你看上去减肥了好多
Wassup,Flam?You look like you lost a few,bro.
要苗条很快就可以
Slim-Fast,baby.
是吗?
Is that what it is,huh?
那帮条子一直在调查你老婆 绝没有开玩笑
The Feds been in your old lady's business,no joke.
翻入栅栏调查  还时常跟踪她
Up in your crib,and  following her around sometimes.
这我都知道
Yeah,I know,man. I know.
我知道你深爱着凯茜
Yo,I know you love Kacee,
但我不认为你跑来这是个好主意
but I don't know if it's a good idea for you to be coming around here.
你是个通缉犯
You're a wanted man.
我被通缉是因为我紧闭牙关
I'm wanted because I kept my mouth shut,
没有把你给吐出来
and I kept you out of Fox River.
我们很清楚这点
See,man,we feel that,
欠你个人情
and we owe you one.
很好 我现在就想要回那人情
Good,'cause I'm collecting right now.
今天我老婆就等着我
My wife is waiting for me today,
我不会舍弃家庭独自离开芝加哥 明白吗?
and I am not leaving Chi-town without my family. You understand?
现在我需要你们的帮助
Now,y'all going to help me.
我们动身吧
Let's roll out.
你去哪里?
Where you going?
送小孩上学去
Take my kid to school.
我知道彩虹轩的事
I know about the Rainbow Room.
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
电话都被监控着
Phone lines are tapped.
我们完整地监听了你和丈夫间的对话
We heard your entire telephone conversation with your husband.
因为你和迪迪都没有预定去纽约的航班
And,since you and Dede aren't booked on any flights to New York,
别告诉我彩虹轩就是曼哈顿的那个餐厅
don't tell me the Rainbow Room is a restaurant in Manhattan.
你现在可以交待和丈夫在哪碰头了
Now,you can tell me where you're meeting your husband,
不然我现在就当着你女儿的面拘捕你
or I can arrest you right in front of your daughter.
你去死吧
You go to hell.
我什么也没有做错
I haven't done anything wrong.
你和一个在逃犯通电话约定今天见面
You spoke with an escaped felon about meeting him today.
你的所作所为足够
You've already done enough
控告你企图协助逃犯
to be charged with attempt to aid and abet.
求你了好吗?  听我说
Please,okay? Listen to me.
一个电话就能把儿童福利院叫来
One phone call and Child Welfare is here,
你会被收监而迪迪会被送往别家抚养
and you're going to County and Dede will be in foster care.
-不要 -别担心
No. Don't worry.
我听说抚养体系的家庭都是一流的
I hear the families in the foster system are top-notch.
你这是要我
You are asking me to choose
在丈夫和女儿之间做出抉择
between my daughter and my husband.
完全正确
Exactly.
怎么样了？
Anything?
我在给福克斯河打电话
I'm on the phone with Fox River.
让他们查查帝博格的档案
Checking Bagwell's file.
查到什么了吗？
Hey,what you got for me?
真的？
Really?
有52次？
52 times?
都是到哪的？
Where?
帕特森  这次我欠你个人情
I owe you,Patterson.
我们要赶很远的路
We got a lot of road to cover.
亚利桑那州  圣戴维镇
没事吧
OK?
到新墨西哥州前 我们不能停顿了
No more stops until we get to New Mexico.
你忘拿你的零钱了
You forgot your change.
哦  谢谢
Yeah,thanks.
-你跑的这么急 -谢了
You were in such a rush. Thanks.
向前走
Keep walking.
好的  继续向前走
Come on,keep walking.
麻烦了
Damn it.
你没必要把车丢了
You don't have to ditch the car.
还可以继续开的
We can keep driving.
不行  那女服务员已经认出我和这车了
Can't. The waitress made me and the car.
这车不能再用了
It's useless.
对不起
Sorry,you know.
也许我们能再找一辆车
Maybe we can find another car.
你以为车会长在路边的树上吗
Cars ain't exactly growing on trees out here.
我们还有400英里要走 而且这里也没有其他的路
We've got 400 miles to go and no way of getting there.
如果我们不能按时找到迈克尔
We don't get to Michael in time,
他就得自己走了
he's going to leave without us.
迈克尔叔叔不会那样做的
Uncle Mike wouldn't do that.
他没的选择
He doesn't have a choice.
那是离开这个国家的唯一机会
It's a one-shot deal out of the country.
我说过了我很抱歉
I said I was sorry.
刚开过路牌显示有个火车站
There was a sign back there for a train station.
-没那么容易 -我们可以沿着路...
It ain't that easy. We'll follow the road...
-没你想的那样简单 -我们不会被发现
It ain't that easy. We won't be seen.
嗨  我不傻
Hey,I'm not an idiot.
我和你一样也在逃亡
I was on the run,too,you know.
是啊 不过你逃亡途中被抓住过
Yeah,you were on the run and you got caught.
没错  我很遗憾我不是一个
Yeah,well,I'm sorry I'm not a pro
像爸爸您那样专业的逃犯
at being a con like you,Dad.
也许我早该在你救出我后就离开你
Maybe I should have just left when you gave me the out,huh?
-不用你管了 -喂  喂
It's not like you care. Whoa,whoa.
别这样
Take it easy.
对不起  没事了
I'm sorry,all right?
对不起  我只是...
Sorry,I'm just...
让我们离开这里
Let's get out of here.
请问你是帕梅拉 马宏夫人吗
Mrs.,uh,Mrs. Pamela Mahone?
是的
Yes?
我是联邦调查局的韦恩 梅瑞克探员
II'm Agent Wayne Merrick,FBI.
我想和你谈谈你前夫的一些事
I'd like to talk to you about your husband.
我有点惊讶你来这查亚历山大的背景
'm surprised...that you're coming to me for a background check on Alex.
这是正常程序
It's standard procedure.
那些即将升官的探员
We run these kind of checks
都会被执行这样的检查
when an agent is about to be promoted to a,to a higher security clearance.
我明白的
No,I know that.
上次他升职的时候我也碰到过
I did this dance the last time he was promoted.
不过我们既然已离婚了
I just figured that since we were divorced-
我是说我真的很少再和他联系了
- I mean,I rarely speak to him
我当然不太清楚他工作上的事
and I certainly don't follow his career.
我真的得在今天把这事做完
I really need to get this done today,
所以 呃 我向你保证
so,uh,I promise I won't take up
一定不会占你很多时间
much of your time.
我给足了我前夫时间 梅瑞克先生
I've given enough time to my ex-husband,Mr. Merrick.
我明白
I see.
呃...
The,uh...
调查局的工作是会影响到家庭的
The Bureau can take its toll on your family.
我明白这点
I understand that.
我前妻是一个...一个探员  呃...
My ex-wife is a... an agent and,um...
这么说吧我明白你的感受
let's just say I know how you feel.
答应我他不会知道我们间的谈话?
Promise me that he won't find out we spoke?
哦 这是完全保密的
Oh,it's totally confidential.
介意我问为什么吗?
Do you mind if I ask why?
坦白说他让我感到害怕
To be perfectly honest,he scares me.
(HOTEL 旅馆)
查询信息？
Information.
请告诉我日落旅馆的电话号码
Hi,I need the number for a Sundown Hotel please.
-哪座城市的? -呃 所有的
What city? Uh,all of them,please.
在南达科他州的皮埃尔有一家
Got one in Pierre,South Dakota.
好的
Okay.
西弗吉尼亚的萨顿也有一家
Another in Sutton,West Virginia
新墨西哥州的吉拉也有一家
and one more in Gila,New Mexico.
堪萨斯州 璀布恩镇
tribune,kansas
能为你效劳吗?
What can I do you for?
请给我一束向日葵
A batch of them sunflowers,please.
恕我冒昧 你的口音听起来
You don't mind me saying,you do not sound
不像是来自堪萨斯的
like you hail from Kansas.
你耳朵真灵
You've got a sharp ear.
呃 我来自阿拉巴马州 我们那称之为黄鹉之州
I hail from what we call the,uh,Yellowhammer State.
为什么来璀布恩?
What brings you to Tribune?
先生?
Sir?
爱情
Romance.
非常感谢
Thank you so much.
有人会受伤的
Somebody's going to get hurt.
联邦探员的火力可比这些强多了
Feds going to be swinging bigger bats than these.
我们必须带上家伙
We gotta have ours.
听着老兄  我们所需要的就是
Look,man,that's all we need
你的轿车 你的卡车 还有勇气
is your car,your truck,and some guts,man.
我们用不着这些
We don't need all of this.
或许我们得再好好想想
Maybe we should think about it.
我说了不!
I said no!
到时会怎样 伙计？
What's going to happen,man,
子弹四处乱飞的时候?
when the bullets start flying,huh?
你能保证我家人不会受到伤害?
Can you guarantee me that my family ain't going to get hurt?
不带武器一旦发生冲突的话
Johnny law is going to be strapped up.
那个菜鸟会被捉起来  我也会被通缉
I'm going in hot.
我想你还是没听懂我的话 小子
I don't think you heard me,little man.
不 我想是你没弄懂我的话
No,I don't think you heard me,bruh.
我不会赤手空拳就去的
I'm not going in naked.
我知道我们说过会帮你
I know we said we'd ride with you on this,
但是我不会不带家伙就去的
but I'm not going in there without some of these.
你想退出 是吧?
You want to punk out,man?
那就退出吧  我一个人也能行
Then punk out,'cause I can do this myself.
没人会退出
Ain't nobody punking out.
我们也不带枪了
And no guns.
但你最好搞清楚
But you'd better be right about this
一旦交起火来
'cause if bullets do start flying,
流血的将是我们
the only blood being spilled is going to be ours.
懂吗?
Feel me?
懂了
I feel you.
克里曼探员
Agent Kellerman.
克里曼探员!
什么事？
Yes.
是关于你要我追踪的那个人凯莉 福斯特
That name you wanted me to track,Kelli Foster.
她订了一张去新墨西哥州的机票 飞机刚抵达
She booked a flight to New Mexico,just landed.
找到是谁了吗?
You got someone on it?
没 但在她租的车上有个名字
No,but we got an ID on her rental car.
我应该告知金姆先生吗?
Should I update Mr. Kim?
不用了 我会亲自处理的
No,I'll take care of this myself.
从一个女服务员那里得到了消息
Got a tip from a waitress
她认为她看到了布伦斯和他儿子
who thinks she saw Burrows and his son
在亚利桑那的圣戴维镇外面
outside St. David,Arizona.
叫队人过去确认
Get a road team out there to confirm.
一有布伦斯的消息
Once they got a bead on Burrows,
马上通知我
notify me immediately.
大家行动! 快点!
Everybody out! Let's go,come on!
谁?
Yeah?
唐克雷蒂  莎拉刚订了张单程机票
Sara Tancredi just booked a one- way ticket across the country.
去哪的?
To where?
新墨西哥州
New Mexico.
对了
Of course.
破解密码有进展吗?
Any luck breaking that code?
呃...
Uh...
这会有帮助的
this helps.
好的
Good.
惠勒!
Wheeler!
长官
Sir.
我要你检查这里面每一个包含NM的组合
Every combination that has NM in it.
看看能否找到有
I want you to check it to see if it contains
新墨西哥州的地名
the name of a location in New Mexico.
马上做！ 明白吗
And I want it done now. Now,you got it.
是的 马上
Yeah,right now.
那么你对亚力克斯又了解多少呢?
So,how well do you know Alex?
他对我的了解比我对他的多多了
He knows me better than I know him.
没错  他是个闷葫芦
He's a closed book,all right.
但他以前可不是这样
But he wasn't always like that.
在我们结婚的头几年
In the first few years of our marriage,
他其实还挺...浪漫的
he was actually... romantic.
但从某一天开始  不知道怎么回事就...
And then,one day,out of nowhere...
就怎么了?
Out of nowhere what?
一切都变了
Everything changed.
他沉迷于离开
He became obsessed with getting out.
离开这段婚姻?
Out of the marriage?
离开这段婚姻
Getting out of the marriage,
也让我离开这个家
getting me out of the house,
离开他的生活
out of his life.
他抛弃了我
He left me.
抛弃了我们两个
He left the both of us.
你说你很怕他
You said you were scared of him.
为什么呢?
Why is that?
他举止变的异常
He started acting strange.
他花全部的时间
Started spending all of his time
在他的花园里搞园艺
in the backyard gardening,of all things.
我是说这个人有洁僻
I mean,the man was a neat freak.
他会把一双鞋扔掉
He'd throw away a pair of shoes
仅仅是因为有一点磨损
if they even got scuffed.
但他却会在那里满身泥土
But he'd be out there all covered in dirt
身边围满了一大包一大包
and surrounded by these huge bags
化肥和碱水
of fertilizer and lye.
我们才刚铺的新草坪
We'd just put this new sod in
他就这么翻开来  又放了个新花坛在上面
and he just tore it all up and planted a flower bed.
有一次我回来找他谈这事
And I went out back once to talk to him
他居然冲我吼叫
and he screamed at me
告诉我不要靠近花园
and said not to come near the garden.
说那是他的
Said that it was his.
我很抱歉  如果你需要...
I'm sorry. If you,uh...
如果你想要休息一下的话...
if you want to take a break...
我只是想听听他的解释
All I wanted was an explanation
为什么事情就草草收场了
why things ended so suddenly.
而亚力克斯给我的答复就是
And all Alex could say was
有时候你会无法控制事态的发展
"Sometimes things happen that are just out of your control."
抱歉
Excuse me.
那么你女儿房里的照片
So the picture in your daughter's bedroom--
就是这里拍的
the exact location where it was taken
就那个旋转木马  对吗?
was a merry-go-round,right?
是的
Yeah.
那你要做的就是在旋转木马那里等着
So,all you have to do is wait by the merry-go-round.
本杰明就等你出现在那儿
Right where Benjamin's expecting you.
有必要动枪吗?
Is that necessary?
我是说  本杰明并不是...
I mean,Benjamin is not...
只是为了以防万一
It's precautionary.
听着  我这么做
Look,I do this,
你要放过我和我的孩子
you leave me and my child alone.
一言为定
You have my word.
我妻子到了吗?
Is my wife there?
是的她在
Yeah,she's here.
那么我们过去接她
Well,let's go get her.
15秒后
In 15 seconds,
一辆黑色吉普会停在
a black Jeep is going to pull up
停车场入口
by the parking lot's entrance.
跑过去
Run to it.
克里斯?
Chris?
快去!
Go!
不行!
I can't.
他们要去抓迪迪
They're going to take Dede.
不会的!
Look,no,they won't.
那家伙是在和她说话吗?
Is that guy talking to her?
找人读他的口形
Get a read on him.
听着  都办好了  快走!
Look,it's taken care of. Go!
走啊!
Go!
她跑了!
She's running!
快追!  快!  快！
Go,go,go,go,go,move,move!
快进来!
Get in!
坐稳了!
Hold on!
目标是一辆2007款黑色吉普.
It's a 2007 black Jeep.
牌照摘掉了
License plates have been removed.
我们开始追击  方向...
We're in pursuit headed...
不!
No!
把车开走
Move the truck. (speaking Spanish)
把车开走! 我说了开走!
Move the truck! I said move it!
我的孩子在哪儿?
Where is my child?
这儿
Here.
迪迪?
Dede?
是我  宝贝儿
Hey,it's me,baby.
听着  我想跟你说
Look,I just want to tell you
一切都会没事的
that everything is going to be okay.
我们马上要全家团员了
We're going to be a family again.
我向你保证
I promise you that.
迪迪在哪儿?
Where is Dede?
他说你接到她了!
He said that you had her!
放松点  宝贝儿
Whoa,whoa. Easy,baby.
镇静点
Easy.
达里斯正在学校里接她
Darius is picking her up from school right now.
迪迪 富兰克林  道森小学
Dede Franklin,Dawson Elementary--
马上把她从学校带走!
I want her pulled from school now!
到底出什么事了  伙计?
What the hell is going on,man?
他们说她在考试
They say she's taking a test,man,
但我觉得他们在拖延时间...
but I think they're stalling.
那关于...
What about,um...
关于奥斯卡  沙尔斯呢?
What about Oscar Shales?
奥斯卡  沙尔斯?
Oscar Shales?
他很重要吗?
Why is he important?
恩  他...
Well,he's,uh...
他是唯一一个从你前夫手上
he's the only fugitive to ever successfully elude your,uh...
成功逃脱的罪犯
your ex-husband.
亚力克斯因为追捕他而筋疲力尽
Alex was consumed with finding him.
我是说在沙尔斯犯下那些罪行之后
I mean,after what Shales did to all of his victims,
他已经这么投入了  谁会去怪他呢?
who could blame him?
他整整一年都在办那个案子
It was all he worked on,all he did for a year.
但我不认为是那个给他压力
But I don't think that it was the stress
不是因为追捕查尔斯
of chasing Shales that caused Alex
才让他行为举止变的怪异
to start behaving erratically.
为什么这么说呢?
Why is that?
因为他是在这案子已经平静了之后才变了的
Because Alex changed  after the trail went cold.
我记得很清晰就象是昨天发生的一样
I remember it like it was yesterday.
他就这么走进厨房
He just walked into the kitchen
在结婚12年之后
after 12 years of marriage
他要我立刻离开那幢房子
and says that he wanted me out of the house immediately.
我永远忘不了那一天
I'll never forget the date.
那是6月15号
It was June 15.
(沙尔斯六月中旬起失踪)
我想我已经了解够了
I think I have everything I need.
但你都没问他的社会背景和教育状况
But you didn't even ask about social history or education.
这些可都是标准程序
That's standard in these checks.
那些都已经搞定了
That's been handled.
我得尽快把这些报告发给
I have to get these reports filed with,
战略行动组
uh,Strategic Operations ASAP.
你是战略行动组的?
You're with Strategic Operations?
他们负责处理这些调查
They handle these checks.
9.11事件重组之后就不是了  梅瑞克先生
Not since the 9/11 realignment,Mr. Merrick.
现在应该是首要情报部门负责这个
The Chief Information Officer does them now.
他们处理了亚力克斯上次的调查
They handled Alex's last check.
当一个探员升到你前夫那么高的位置的时候
When an agent reaches a level as high as your ex-husband's,
战略行动组又会接手的
S.O. takes over. Again.
官僚主义那一套
Bureaucracies.
谢谢您的咖啡
Thank you for the coffee.
听着  把她带出来就行了!
Look,just get her out of there.
他们来了
They're here.
-不要!  我们要走了! -别担心
No! See,we got to go! No,don't worry about it.
把车发动起来!  去吧!
Just get the car started,all right? Go!
爸爸!
Daddy!
宝贝儿!
Hey,baby!
准备出发了吗?
You ready to go?
我们去哪儿呢?
Where are we going?
迪斯尼乐园
Disneyland.
你不能带走她  富兰克林先生!
You can't take her.Mr. Franklin,please.
FBI
来吧  我们走!
Come on,let's go!
快宝贝儿  快走!
Go,baby. Go,baby.
快  快!
Go,go,go,go,go,go!
富兰克林把孩子带走了!
Franklin has the child!
重复一遍  富兰克林把孩子带走了!
Repeat,Franklin has the child!
晚上好  赫兰德太太
Evening,Mrs. Hollander.
今晚你看上去真迷人
Don't you look lovely this evening.
你应该告诉我你是个什么样的人
You should have told me what you were!
上帝啊  我居然让你亲近了
My God,I let you near
我的孩子们!
my children!
别以为我会忘记你家门庭什么样子
Don't think I won't remember what your front steps look like.
过来  离马路远点
Come on,get away from the road.
你想被抓住吗?
You want to get caught?
我...
I,uh...
我看到你在观察那些女孩儿
I saw you checking out those girls
就在那餐馆那地方
back at the diner.
啥?
What?
得了吧  别装了
Come on. Fess up.
不是  我只是看看她们是不是注意到我们了
No. I was just making sure that they weren't staring at us.
用什么注意?  她们的美臀？
With what? Their asses?
巴拿马的美女
Beautiful girls in Panama.
她们都喜欢美国人
They love Americans.
酷
Cool.
你什么时候开始关注女生了?
So,uh,how long have you known about girls?
有段时间了
Long enough.
什么时候开始的?
Since when?
13岁
Thirteen.
13岁?
Thirteen?
和谁?
With who?
唐娜  安塞姆
Donna Anselmi.
就是隔壁那小姑娘?
She was the kid next door.
她好象是...
She was about...
她比我大四岁
She's four years older than me.
你妈妈还花钱让她教你法语
Your mom was paying her for French lessons.
那是  她是挣到钱了
Well,she earned the money.
过来点
Come on.
离路远点
Away from the road.
你还是离太近了  走吧
You're still way too close. Let's go.
你想学点小窍门儿吗?  格雷丝?
You want to learn some tricks,Gracey?
什么窍门儿?
Like what?
好
Yeah.
我让你进入我的生活
I let you into my life.
对
Yeah.
27!
Twenty seven!
晚上好  赫兰德太太
Evening,Mrs. Hollander.
感觉如何啊  小畜生?
How are you feeling,little Teddy?
明天
Tomorrow.
帕姆  我现在真没空和你谈
Pam,I really can't talk right now.
那我该过会儿再打来
Maybe I should call back.
你是谁?
Who is this?
我想你已经知道了
I think you already know.
如果你敢动帕姆
If you've done anything to Pam...
或者我儿子一根毫毛...
or my boy...
你我都知道你的家人没事
We both know your family's fine.
尽管帕姆对你抛妻弃子感到心烦
Although,Pam did seem a little upset about you leaving.
但是你确实逼于无奈  是不是?
But then you had to,didn't you?
因为你不能让她找到
'Cause you couldn't let her find out.
找到什么?
Find out about what?
奥斯卡  沙尔斯还记得吗?
Oscar Shales. You remember?
那个跑掉的家伙
The one that got away.
除非他没走多远
Except he didn't get too far.
是不是?
Did he?
呃... 你渐渐不行了  斯科菲尔德
Uh... you're slipping,Scofield.
也许
Maybe.
我来假设一种情况
Let's hypothesize for a moment.
假设我就是那个抓住沙尔斯的人
Let's pretend I was the one who caught Shales.
我觉得我不会只是把这个疯子
I don't think I could of just handed that psychopath
送上法庭那么简单
over to the courts,
因为他让我追了那么久
not after he'd eluded me for so long.
让我窘态尽出
Made me look bad.
你假想过头了 小子
You've been out in the sun way too long,kid.
你们FBI的人过着美好的生活
You feds make a nice living,
但是不会有钱到去翻掉昂贵的草皮
but not so nice you go around tearing up expensive sod.
除非你要挖个洞
Not unless you had to do a little digging,
除非你要藏什么东西
not unless you wanted to hide something...
或是藏什么人
or someone.
这就是那些碱液的作用
That's what all the lye was for.
不是吗?
Wasn't it?
有两种碱液
See,because there are two kinds of lye.
少量的是第一种
Small amounts,the first kind
给园丁用的
can be a garderner's best friend.
还有另外一种大剂量的 用来让尸体腐烂分解
And large bags,the other kind decomposes bodies.
你该去写推理小说了
Ah,you should write mystery novels.
我目前虽然不了解你
Now,I don't know about you,
但要是我把某人埋在自家后院
but if I buried someone in my own backyard,
我一定会整天都想着它
I'd think about it all the time.
我会想...
I'd think...
我会想或许我该把尸体换个地方
I'd think maybe I should move that body.
但我记起来DNA渗入到泥土里
But then I remember,DNA leeches into soil.
所以即使尸体不在了
So even when the body was gone,
证据仍旧在那里
the proof of what I'd done would still be there.
我能想像这是种什么感觉
I can imagine how it feels.
这压力...
The pressure...
这持续的恐惧
the constant fear.
这不是人能够承受的
It's more than a man can bear.
我现在想给你个机会
I'm going to give you a chance.
放手不要管
Back off.
让我和家人消失
Let me and my family disappear.
作为回报  我会保守你的小秘密
And in return,I'll keep your little secret.
这主意如何?
How does that sound?
就像临终遗言
Like a dead man talking.
我知道这不是你要的结果
I know it's not how you wanted this to play out.
但是有时事情的发展
But sometimes things happen that are just
你也控制不了
out of your control.
现在就是这种情形
This is one of those times.
小心你自己
Take care of yourself.
我会很快见到你  迈克尔
I'll see you soon,Michael.
还有  迈克尔
Oh,and,Michael,
可能会比你想像的更快
it just may be sooner than you think.
睡得舒服吗?
Did you have a nice nap?
梦见12岁的小朋友在跳舞了?
Visions of 12 year olds dancing in your head?
你们这是非法闯入民宅
You're trespassin'.
没人住在这里了  黄毛
Nobody lives here anymore,Goldilocks.
看起来主人家听说某人要重返社会
Seems the owner hit the bricks as soon as she heard
就离开了
a certain someone had reentered society.
走得很匆忙  还落下点东西
Left in a hurry,too,even left some stuff behind.
所以这里就是帝博格实践
So this is where Theodore practiced
"性变态大全"的地方
Pervert Knows Best.
这里
This...
就是他享用家庭晚餐的地方
is where he had his family supper.
还有那里
And that
我相信就是
I believe is where
你和赫兰德女士表示你们爱的地方
you and Ms. Hollander expressed your love.
告诉我  小畜生
Tell me,little Teddy,
你是不是让她穿着登顿医生的衣服
did you make her wear Dr. Denton's
还打扮成男妓才让你有感觉的?
and hold a lunch box to help you get all worked up?
布拉德利  我根本不期盼一个
Bradley,I couldn't possibly expect a grown man
还和妈妈住在一起成年男子
who still lives with his momma
会明白
to understand
爱情的诡计
the machinations of love.
你想知道我们怎么找到你的?
You want to know how we found you?
52封你寄到这地址的信
52 mash notes,sent by you,to this address.
所有的信都乞求赫兰德女士
All of them beggin' Ms. Hollander
原谅你这小白脸
to take your white-trash ass back.
每封信最终都被
And every one of them
退回到福克斯河监狱
boomeranged to Fox River marked "return to sender."
警卫们
Oh,the guards
看了以后笑死了  是吧盖瑞?
had a real laugh readin' 'em,didn't we,Geary?
我们笑翻了
Oh,damn right we did.
这可真污秽
That is one mangy
看看你的手
lookin' paw you got there,slick.
怎么搞成这样 有个童子军反抗你施暴了?
What happened,a Boy Scout fought back?
盖瑞
Geary.
现在你得告诉我
Now you're going to tell me
你把韦斯特莫兰德的钱放哪儿了?
where you stashed Westmoreland's money,
否则我就像拔鸡毛一样
or I'm going to pluck you like a chicken,
一针一针地拆掉
stitch by stitch.
好吧  你想知道钱在哪儿?
Fine,you want to know where the money is?
我昨晚花了一大把钱在你老妈身上
I did spend a whole bunch of it last night on your momma.
答错
Wrong answer.
过来  宝贝
Come here,baby.
你好吗?
How are you?
Hm? You good? Yeah.
她没事
She's okay.
-宝贝 -嗯
Baby. Yeah.
我们现在该怎么办?
What do we do now?
你打算怎么做?
What are we going to do?
上车再买票
Get a ticket on the train.
过来
Come on.
在这儿等着火车
Just wait here until the train comes.
距离吉拉镇73英里
Two Caucasian males on foot,
两白种男人徒步逃出威尔考克斯火车站
fleeing the Willcox station.
LJ!
别动
Don't move.
求求你  他跟这没关系
Please. Please. He's got nothing to do with this.
脸朝下  你们两个
Face down. Both of you
-脸朝下! 快! -求求你
face down! Now! Please.
铐上他们
Cuff 'em.
LJ  对不起
LJ,I'm sorry.
嫌疑犯被抓获
Suspect in custody.
可能身份林肯  布伦斯
Possible ID: Lincoln Burrows.
对不起  LJ  对不起
I'm sorry. LJ,I'm sorry.